Dan Nguyen

Melbourne, Australia daan.nguyen@gmail.com http://daan-nguyen.github.io 0402 830 449

05.2012 - Current

Software Engineer

Adaptable, motivated and personable software engineer with 7 years of experience over a range of technologies and platforms in an enterprise environment focusing on web applications & content management.

Genuinely passionate about technology with a keen eye for detail and a strong personal interest in design, typography, user experience and always keen to learn more. Currently seeking an opportunity to grow my front-end capability and join a team of like-minded individuals to help solve challenging problems and deliver beautifully coded, quality front-ends and applications that I can be proud of.

Experience

Web developer at National Australia Bank (NAB) in Melbourne since 2007. In-depth experience across the full development stack from backend development in Java and C# to front-end development dealing with responsive design and cross-browser compatibility. Strong knowledge and experience with OOP, design patterns and development practices such as version control & continuous integration.

Application Development & Testing, NAB, Web Developer

Established NAB UI—an internal framework based on Bootstrap—as the first step to improve the presentation, usability, compatibility and consistency of internal web application front-ends whilst reducing development effort, costs and the reliance on a specific browser environment as internal applications are made available to devices beyond the desktop.

NAB UI has been enthusiastically adopted across a number of teams for in-flight projects and continues to be marketed via team demonstrations and successful application launches.

- Designed and developed user experience and front-end for internal Relationships & Services application, translating the application from a DOS based front-end to a Java Spring MVC web application that will improve usability & accessibility for up to 10,000 front line staff. Test driven development with full suite of Selenium functional tests integrated into Jenkins CI process.
- Seconded to Mobile & Emerging Technology to develop an administration application built on AngularJS consuming internal REST APIs for NAB Flik (mobile consumer to consumer payments platform).
- Lead front-end development for nabbroker.com.au based on agency design.
 Delivered cross-browser, responsive front-end consisting of HTML/CSS & C# .NET custom user controls integrated into templates for OpenText Red Dot CMS. Build completed within 6 week deadline leveraging agile methodologies.
- Experience working as part of larger project teams (15-25) and in small focused teams (4-6) using agile methodologies and practices

04.2011 - 05.2012

Business Intelligence Solutions Centre, NAB, BI Developer

- Worked on pilot project introducing Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise into the organisation, developing standards and processes for use of OBIEE within BISC.
- Developed self-service universes & automated reporting for business stakeholders using Business Objects Webi analytics tools.

02.2007 - 04.2011

Web Applications – Intranet Portal, NAB, **Graduate/Analyst Programmer**

- Lead development of J2EE Business Objects Viewer web application to implement upgrades required to integrate with Business Objects XI Release 3.
- Implementation of new visual design as part of enterprise intranet refresh.
- Designed & developed J2EE intranet video delivery portlet & sub-site to replace terrestrial television delivery of NABtv, leveraged existing file delivery infrastructure to minimise network impact.
- Responsible for development and support of enterprise intranet based on IBM WebSphere Portal, IBM Web Content Manager, Autonomy Search, Confluence Wiki and other J2EE web applications including Business Objects report viewer serving ~5,000 unique reports to thousands of front line and back office staff.

Education

2002 - 2006 1998 - 2001 BEng (Hons) in Software, BCom in Accounting, University of Melbourne Victorian Certificate of Education, TER of 98.70, Melbourne High School

Skills Summary

Server-side Strong Java, C#/ASP .NET

Moderate Perl, PL/SQL

Front-end Strong HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AngularJS

Bootstrap/Foundation, SASS/SCSS, Less

Moderate KnockoutJS, TypeScript

Version Control Git, ClearCase, TFS

Other Tools Selenium, JUnit, NUnit, Jenkins CI, Jira, Mercury/ALM,

Photoshop, Eclipse, Visual Studio 2010

Storage Oracle, IBM DB2, MS-SQL

Non-commercial C, Objective-C, PHP, MySQL, nodeJS

References

References available upon request.